Guide to the New-York Historical Society Poster Collection 1790-2022 PR 55
New-York Historical Society
- Series V. Political Posters, 1840-2008; 100 item(s) (approximately)
  - Subseries V.2 State and Local Elections, 1856-1958
    - "Twelfth Ward Whig Nominations!", undated (Folder FF 05-13)
      Poster printed by J.C. Kelley & J.A. Fraetas, Printers. Alpheus Sherman, John A. Sidell, and John G. Kip were all nominated.
    - "For District Attorney...Wm Travers Jerome", c.1901 (Folder FF 05-14)
      Poster copyrighted by Poch Bros. and published by The Freytag Printing Company (with union printing label). On back, in pencil, "E.B. Child. Jan. 1939".
    - Ballot for Mayor of New York City (Seth Low) and other offices, 1902 (Folder FF 05-14)
      On back, in pencil, "April 18, 1962. Univ. of Pa." Seth Low was the mayorial candidate for both the Republican and Citizens Union tickets. Candidates for other positions were, Denis O'Brien, Frederic W. Hinrichs, Edward J. McQuire, Henry Bischoff, Ralph Trautmann, and Cyrus Sulzberger.
    - "Blot Out the Saloon!" Prohibition Candidates for Gov./Lt. Gov., 1902 (Folder FF 05-14)
      Poster sponsored by J.H. Durkee, Chairman of Prohibition State Committee. Alfred L. Manierre was Prohibition Party's candidate for Governor and John A. Hartman was the candidate for Lieut.-Governor.
    - "Regular Democratic Nomination For Mayor...George B. McClellan", c.1903 (Folder FF 05-14)
      2 copies. Poster sponsored by the Metropolitan Equipment Company and has a union printing label. Acquisition date(?), on back, in pencil, Dec 1, 1932 on copy 1. Copy 2, on back, in pencil, "E.B. Child. Jan. 1939".
    - Public Officials of the Borough of the Bronx, 1903 (Folder FF 05-14)
      Poster was a supplement to "The North Side News," December 20, 1903, and features images of the public officials.
    - "Fusion's Candidate for President...Bronx...Joseph I. Berry of Fordham", 1903 (Folder FF 05-14)
      Poster was published as a suppplement to Bronx Borough Record and Times, October 11, 1903. Acquisition date(?), on back, in pencil, Feb. 15, 1938.
    - "$30,000 in Rewards for Arrest...Repeaters, Floaters...Election Law...", c.1908 (Folder FF 05-14)
      Poster has an allied printing union label. Red lettering on light brown background. Directs citizens to see circular of The Citizens Union for terms of offer. On back, in pencil, "April 18, 1962. Univ. of Pa."
    - Republican Party list of Delegates to the 15th Congress and Assembly Districts Republican Convention, 1908 (Folder FF 05-14)
      The list of names was from the Borough of Manhattan, 7th Election District, 15th Assembly District, and the named persons were to elect delegates to either the Reblican National Convention or the Republican State Convention. Acquisition date(?), on back, in pencil, March 23, 1936.
    - "For District Attorney...Charles S. Whitman", c.1909 (Folder FF 05-14)
      Poster has a union printing label. Acquisition date(?), on front, in pencil, Dec. 1, 1932.
    - Charles S. Whitman (Governor of New York, 1915-1918), c.1914 (Folder FF 05-14)
      Poster copyrighted by Pirie MacDonald, N.Y. and published by G. Prince, N.Y. Poster features a three-quarters portrait of Whitman with his name running along the bottom. Probably for his run for Governor. Acquisition date(?), on front, in pencil, Dec 2, 1932.
    - "A Man of Deeds - Not Words...Charles S. Whitman", c.1914 (Folder FF 05-14)
      Poster copyrighted by Pirie MacDonald, N.Y. and published (with union printing label) by G. Prince, N.Y. Poster features same image as above-listed poster but includes a pledge by Candidate that he is a candidate for the nomination for Governor in the Republican primary and no other, that he has never been subservient to any political boss, and that he has not enetered into any deal with anybody regarding this nomination. On back, in pencil, "E.B. Child. Jan. 1939".
    - "Independence League Candidate for Municipal Court Justice...John Davis", undated (Folder FF 05-14)
      Poster published by North Side News Job Print (with allied printing union label) and features an image of the candidate. The Independence League party was started by William Randolph Hearst in about 1906 and and coninued in New York City until about 1911. Acquisition date(?), on front, in pencil, Dec. 2, 1932.
    - "Honesty...Vote for Mayor Low and Keep the Grafters Out", 1903 (Folder FF 05-15)
      The poster was made of "Trade Crystaloid" and manufactured by The Whitehead & Hoag Co., N.Y. (with union made label). Poster features vibrant colors with an image of a woman as greek statue and City Hall in background. On front, in pencil, "April 18, 1962. Univ. of Pa."
    - Order of the Acorns. Office of the Great Oak, Oak Leaf No. 1-22, 1903 (Folder FF 05-15)
      These circulars were printed by Lipshitz Press, Blanchard Press, and Economist Press, in English, German, Italian, and Hebrew. Many are two-sided. All are anti-Tammany and appeal to "Vote for Low". For the most part, there is at least one copy of each Oak Leaf in the collection, many are stamped "Library of the University of Pennsylvania" with a date of April 18, 1962. Some copies have acquisition date(?), in pencil, March 18, 1918. Several circulars have caricatures, many drawn by Quincy Scott or reprinted from "New York World".
    - Documents Issued by City Vigilance League. "Vote for Low", 1903 (Folder FF 05-15)
      The City Vigilance League issued at least 24 documents, denoted as "1903, Document _." The collection has most of the documents up to Document 24, and in several cases, multiple copies of the single sheet "Documents". Most are stamped with a "Library of the University of Pennsylvania" and have a date written on them April 18, 1962. Other copies have an acquisition date(?) of March 18, 1918. All the sheets have a union printing label. Many of the "Documents" have caricatures drawn by D. McCarthy.
    - "New York Looks to the Police to Stand for Decency and Honesty!", 1903 (Folder FF 05-15)
      Reprint of letter to the editor from Brooklyn Eagle and "The Police in this Campaign" from the Evening Sun. Acquisition date(?), on back, in pencil, April 18, 1962. Univ. of Pa.
    - "Lest We Forget -- Vote for Low":, 1903 (Folder FF 05-15)
      Poster issued by the Republican Club of the City of New York. Caricature drawn by Colin S. Craig. Has union printing label. Acquisition date(?) on back, in pencil, April 18, 1962. Univ. of Pa.
    - "Grout Roasted by Grout" (Low for Mayor), 1903 (Folder FF 05-15)
      Pamphlet issued by the Republican Club of the City of New York and has a union printing label. Acquisition date(?): April 18, 1962, Univ. of Pa.
    - "Citizens' Union Against Tammany...Vote for Low...", c.1903 (Folder FF 05-16)
      Published by The Metropolitan Printing Co. (with a union printing label). Red and blue lettering against light brown background. Acquisition date(?), on back, in pencil, April 18, 1962. Univ. of Pa.
    - "Charities...Mayor Low Protected the City's Poor", 1903 (Folder FF 05-16)
      2 copies. Poster copyrighted by Citizen's Union and published by The Metropolitan Printing Company, N.Y. (with union printing label). Poster features an image of a woman as a greek statue in front of City Hall(?). Copy 1: Acquisition date(?) on front, in pencil, Dec. 1, 1932. Copy 2: Acquisition date(?), on back, in pencil, April 18, 1962. Univ. of Pa.
    - "Anti-Tammany Fusion Candidate for Mayor. Seth Low", c.1903 (Folder FF 05-16)
      Poster published by The Metropolitan Printing Co., N.Y. (with union printing label). Acquisition date(?) on back, in pencil, April 18, 1962. Univ. of Pa.
    - "Schools...Mayor Low is Spending $15,000,000 for Schools", 1903 (Folder FF 05-16)
      Poster copyrighted by Citizen's Union and published by The Metropolitan Printing Company, N.Y. (with union printing label). Poster features an image of a woman as a greek statue in front of school(?). Acquisition date(?) on back, in pencil, April 18, 1962. Univ. of Pa.
    - "Tenements...Mayor Low Fights Disease in the Tenements", 1903 (Folder FF 05-16)
      Poster copyrighted by Citizen's Union and published by The Metropolitan Printing Company, N.Y. (with union printing label). Poster features an image of a woman as a greek statue in front of tenement. Acquisition date(?) on back, in pencil, April 18, 1962. Univ. of Pa.
    - "Honesty...Vote for Mayor Low", 1903 (Folder FF 05-16)
      Poster copyrighted by Citizen's Union and published by The Metropolitan Printing Company, N.Y. (with union printing label). Poster features an image of a woman as a greek statue in front of City Hall(?). Acquisition date(?) on back, in pencil, April 18, 1962. Univ. of Pa.
    - "Transportation...Mayor Low has pushed New Subways...", 1903 (Folder FF 05-16)
      Poster copyrighted by Citizen's Union and published by The Metropolitan Printing Company, N.Y. (with union printing label). Poster features an image of a woman as a greek statue in front of bridge. Acquisition date(?) on back, in pencil, April 18, 1962. Univ. of Pa.
    - "Police...Mayor Low Protects the Poor against Vice", 1903 (Folder FF 05-16)
      Poster copyrighted by Citizen's Union and published by The Metropolitan Printing Company, N.Y. (with union printing label). Poster features an image of a woman as a greek statue in front of Police Headquarters(?). Acquisition date(?) on back, in pencil, April 18, 1962. Univ. of Pa.
    - "Health...Under Mayor Low A Smaller Death Rate", 1903 (Folder FF 05-16)
      Poster copyrighted by Citizen's Union and published by The Metropolitan Printing Company, N.Y. (with union printing label). Poster features an image of a woman as a greek statue in front of water and piers(?). Acquisition date(?) on back, in pencil, April 18, 1962. Univ. of Pa.
    - "Parks...Mayor Low Opened Fourteen Parks and Playgrounds", 1903 (Folder FF 05-16)
      Poster copyrighted by Citizen's Union and published by The Metropolitan Printing Company, N.Y. (with union printing label). Poster features an image of a woman as a greek statue in front of park. Acquisition date(?) on back, in pencil, April 18, 1962. Univ. of Pa.
    - "District Attorney...George Gordon Battle", 1909 (Folder FF 05-17)
      Poster copyrighted by Pach Bros., N.Y. and printed by Van Dyck Gravure Co., N.Y. (with union printing label). Feautes a three-quarter face portrait image of the democratic candidate. Acquisition date(?) on front, in pencil, Dec. 1, 1932.
    - Reproduction of Presidential Election Ballot, N.Y. County, 1912 (Folder FF 05-17)
    - "For Mayor...John Purroy Mitchel", 1913 (Folder FF 05-17)
      Small poster copyrighted by Campbell Studios (with printing union label). Published by Mitchel Leagues Headquarters on Greeley Square. On back, in pencil, "Rec'd March 12, 1945".
    - "Samuel Seabury...Candidate for Governor of New York State", 1916 (Folder FF 05-17)
      Small poster printed by Van Dyck Gravure Co., N.Y. (with a union printing label) and features a full face portrait image of the candidate.
    - Republican Candidate for Member of Congress (25th NY)...J. Mayhew Wainwright, c.1923 (Folder FF 05-18)
      Poster has a union printing label and features a full face portrait image of candidate. Acquisition date(?) on back, in pencil, Oct. 10, 1946.
    - Republican nomination for State Senator (21st District) Richard W. Lawrence, c.1924 (Folder FF 05-18)
      Poster printed by Fleming & Carnrick, New York. Features a full face portrait image of the candidate. Acquisition date(?) on front, in pencil, Dec. 2, 1932.
    - Republican-Citizen's Ticket...Douglas Mathewson...Justice...N.Y. Supreme Court, 1925 (Folder FF 05-18)
      Poster has a union printing label and features a full face portrait image of candidate. Slogan is that he'would be a just judge of the state. On back, in pencil, "Gift of Hon. Douglas Mathewson. Rec'd March 12, 1945".
    - Copy of H.R. 4798 of the 69th Congress, 1st Session, 1925 (Folder FF 05-18)
      Mr. Davey (Dem. Ohio) introduced bill to grant President temporary powers to reorganize Government Service.
    - The Associated Republicans of the 19th Assembly District Campaign Fundraising letter, 1926 (Folder FF 05-18)
      The Associated Republicans officers were Lucius M. Stanton, William B. Cragin, Fred F. Waters, Warren C. Crane, Le Roy D. Ball, and Arnold C. Weil. Republicans stance was to defeat Tammany. Letter lists Executive Committee and Campaign Committee. Acquisition date(?) on back, in pencil, March 23, 1926.
    - "The New York Evening World...Primary Election...Garvin vs. Hecht", undated (Folder FF 05-19)
      Poster features bold black type on beige background. The New York Evening World merged in 1931 to become The New York World-Telegram. On front, in pencil, "EB Child/39".
    - "For Mayor...Otto T. Bannard", 1909 (Folder FF 05-19)
      2 copies (slight variation). Full-face portrait image of candidate copyrighted by Pach Bros N.Y. in 1909. Poster printed by The Freytag Printing Co. with a union printing label. Acquisition date(?) on front in pencil: Copy 1, Mar. 21, 1933 and Copy 2, Dec. 1, 1932.
    - NRA (National Recovery Act) "We Do Our Part" posters and stickers, c.1933 (Folder FF 05-19)
      Posters and stickers feature the "Blue Eagle", a symbol that the entity was doing its part to end the Great Depression.
    - "Recovery Party for District Attorney New York County...Ferdinand Pecora", 1933 (Folder FF 05-19)
    - "Robert McC. Marsh. Fusion Candidate for Justice...", c.1933 (Folder FF 05-19)
      Poster printed by Tenny Press, New York (with union printing label) and features a full face portrait image of candidate.
    - "Irving Ben Cooper for City Court Judge...Win with Fusion", 1933 (Folder FF 05-19)
    - "Win with Fusion...Leonard Bronner, Jr. for Assembly...", 1933 (Folder FF 05-19)
    - "Elect Moses H. Grossman...Justice...(Recovery Ticket)", 1933 (Folder FF 05-19)
      Poster printed by Burland Printing Company, Inc., New York (with union printing label) and features a full face portrait image of candidate.
    - "The Only Way to Beat All Bosses...Vote Fusion!", 1933 (Folder FF 05-19)
      Poster of political cartoon drawn by Rollin Kirby and published in New York World-Telegram, Saturday, September 30, 1933.
    - "Regular Organization Candidate...Tammany Hall...For Alderman...Edward Cassidy", c.1933 (Folder FF 05-19)
      Poster printed by Press of John Otto (with union printing label) and features a full face portrait image of candidate.
    - George Trosk (Republican and City Fusion) for Justice of the Supreme Court, 1933 (Folder FF 05-19)
      Poster features a full-face portrait image of candidate and has a union printing label. In this election, Trosk sued to remove other candidates from places on the Recovery Party, or McKee, ticket.
    - "Vote for Jacob Gould Schurman, Jr. (Fusion) for District Attorney", 1933 (Folder FF 05-19)
      Poster printed by Wm. T. Wager, Bronx, NY. and has a union printing label. Features a full-face portrait image of candidate.
    - "Nathan Straus, Jr. (Recovery) for President of the Board of Aldermen", 1933 (Folder FF 05-19)
      Poster printed by Burland Printing Company, Inc., New York with union printing label. Features full face portrait image of candidate and promotes for Mayor, McKee, and for Comptroller, Cuff.
    - "For Comptroller...James I. Cuff (Recovery)", 1933 (Folder FF 05-19)
      Poster printed by Herald-Nathan Press, Inc., New York, and has a union printing label and a NRA (National Recovery Administration) label. Features a full-face portrait image of candidate.
    - "Re-elect Edward R. Koch (Recovery)...Justice of the Supreme Court", 1933 (Folder FF 05-19)
      2 copies. Poster was printed by Wm. T. Wager, NYC, and has a union printing label. Features a three-quarters face portrait image of candidate.
    - "William M. Brouillard (Fusion) for County Clerk, New York County", 1933 (Folder FF 05-19)
      Poster printed by Tenny Press, N.Y.C. and has a union printing label. Features full-face portrait image of candidate.
    - "O'Brien (Democrat) For Mayor", 1933 (Folder FF 05-19)
      2 copies. Small paper signs with union printing label.
    - "Elect Frank J. Prial (Democrat) Comptroller", 1933 (Folder FF 05-19)
      Poster issued by the Non-Partisan Committee for Frank J. Prial and has a union printing label. Features a full-face portrait image of candidate.
    - Denis O'L. Cohalan (Democrat) for Justice of the Supreme Court, 1933 (Folder FF 05-19)
      Poster has union printing label and features full-face portrait image of candidate.
    - "Demonstrate Against War and Fascism" March, 1934 (Folder FF 05-19)
      Photocopy of nnotice. March sponsored by the International Labor Defense on the 20th anniversary of The World War.
    - "Recover with Republicans" Stickers, 1936 (Folder FF 05-19)
      2 stickers. Published by National Republican Builders, Inc. Slogan: "Build Business, Banish Borrowing, Balance Budget". Acquisition date(?) on back, in pencil, Apr. 26, 1937.
    - First Voters League, Inc. information sheets, 1936 (Folder FF 05-19)
      2 sheets. Acquisition date(?) on back of both sheets, Nov. 19, 1936.
    - Vote for Hamilton Fish, Jr./William Ziegler Primary Election Political Cartoon, 1936 (Folder FF 05-19)
      Political cartoon drawn by Herb Perry. Acquisition date(?) on back Apr. 2, 1936.
    - American Taxpayers League, Inc. Appeal, 1936 (Folder FF 05-19)
      Acquisition date(?) on back, in pencil, Oct. 31, 1936.
    - The National Republican Builders, Inc. "A Red 'Baedeker'" Reprint, 1936 (Folder FF 05-19)
      2 copies. One reprint is from The Boston American; the other from The New York American. Acquisition dates(?) on back, Oct. 31, 1936 and Apr. 26, 1937.
    - Social Security Board Deduction Notice, 1936 (Folder FF 05-19)
      Acquisition date(?) on back, in pencil, Nov. 19, 1936.
    - Reprint of Letter to Editor of New York Times about Women voting to lower taxes, 1936 (Folder FF 05-19)
    - Reprint from N.Y. Sun on false allegation that Al Landon Anti-Semitic, 1936 (Folder FF 05-19)
    - Association for Economy and Tax Equality Informational Pamphlet, 1936 (Folder FF 05-19)
      Acquisition date(?) on back, in pencil, Nov. 20, 1936.
    - League for Constitutional Government Advertisement for Booklet, 1936 (Folder FF 05-19)
      Acquisition date(?) on front, in pencil, June 27, 1936.
    - Reprint from The Woman Republican on Voting in New York State, 1936 (Folder FF 05-19)
    - "The Ship of State, Adrift" New York Herald Tribune Published Letter, 1936 (Folder FF 05-19)
      Letter written by Robert A. Bohlen. Acquisition date(?) on back, in pencil, Nov. 19, 1936.
    - "Public Sale" of One Democratic Platform Notice, 1936 (Folder FF 05-19)
      Handwritten at the bottom: "11.19.1936.... The above is a true copy of pamphlet circulated by the Crusades History (?) [signed] Maris(?) Wilde".
    - Reprint of Boston Post article on WPA and Communist Party in New York, 1936 (Folder FF 05-19)
      Acquisition date(?) on back, Oct. 31, 1936.
    - "Expenditures and Taxes" Informational Poster, 1936 (Folder FF 05-19)
      Acquisition date(?) on back, in pencil, June 1936.
    - Democratic Rally in Belmar, New Jersey, 1936 (Folder FF 05-19)
      Notice paid for by Young Men's Democratic Club of Belmar. Acquisition date(?) on back, in pencil, Nov. 20, 1936.
    - New Jersey Political Advertisements for Candidates in Federal and Local Elections, 1936 (Folder FF 05-19)
      Advertisements published in The Coast Advertiser, Belmar, N.J. on Friday, October 30, 1936.
    - "To The Half-Starved Unemployed Voters of New York City" Flyer, 1936 (Folder FF 05-19)
    - "Wake Up America! The Voices of Forgotten..." Flyer, 1936 (Folder FF 05-19)
      Flyer copyrighted and written by Gustave C. Hoenes of San Fernando, California, and printed in the United States. Acquisition date(?) on back, in pencil, June 1, 1936.
    - Republican National Finance Committee for New York City Newsletter, 1936 (Folder FF 05-19)
      Acquisition date(?) on back, in pencil, Nov. 9, 1936.
    - Belmar, New Jersey, Election Notice for November 3, 1936 (Folder FF 05-19)
      On back, "*Dr. Frederick Griffith. Nov. 20, 1936".
    - "Hear Robert Minor Communist Candidate for Governor of N.Y. State", 1936 (Folder FF 05-19)
      Poster printed by Rotograph, N.Y. Auspices of Communist Party.
    - 19th Anniversary Celebration of the Russian Revolution, 1936 (Folder FF 05-19)
      Poster printed by Rotocraft, N.Y. and auspices: State Committee, Communist Party. Celebration held at St. Nicholas Palace.
    - Platform of the Social Labor Party of the State of New York, 1936 (Folder FF 05-19)
      Published by Socialist Pamphlets New York Labor News Company.
    - "Re-elect W. Warren Barbour United States Senator (N.J.)", 1936 (Folder FF 05-19)
      Poster paid for by George R. Dye, Campaign Manager, and has a union printing label. Features full-face portrait image of candidate. On back, in pencil, "Gift of Comm. Frederick Griffith. Dec. 17, 1936".
    - Vote for George Backer...American Labor Party Candidate, 1937 (Folder FF 05-19)
      Acquisition date(?) on back, in pencil, Nov. 1937.
    - The National Republican Builders, Inc., Outline of Work and Future Plans, c.1937 (Folder FF 05-19)
      Small flyer outlining past activities and future plans. Directors of organization were: Arthur A. Ballantine, Mrs. Preston Davie, John Jay Hopkins, Daniel Kenefick, Walter S. Mack, Jr., Julian S. Mason, Ogden I. Mills, Nicholas Roosevelt, and Mrs. George Wyeth. Acquisition date(?), on back, in pencil, Apr. 26, 1937.
    - American Labor Party Invitation to Speech of Newbold Morris, 1938 (Folder FF 05-19)
      Poster printed by Rotograph, N.Y. Newbold Morris was President of the Council of the City of New York.
    - "Re-elect Assemblyman Langdon W. Post" Banner, 1932 (Folder FF 05-20)
      Banner with gromets in each corner was printed by Collison & Klingman with a union printing label. On back, Harry B. Hoffman. Mar 7, 1940.
    - "NRA (National Recovery Administration) Member...We Do Our Part", c.1933 (Folder FF 05-20)
      2 copies (slight variations). Red background with white type and NRA seal.
    - Albert Marinelli (Democrat) for County Clerk, New York County, c.1933 (Folder FF 05-20)
    - Re-elect Martha Byrne (Democrat) for Register, New York County, c.1933 (Folder FF 05-20)
      Poster has union printing label and features a full-face portrait image of candidate.
    - "American Labor Party...LaGuardia for Mayor...Vladeck for Councilman...", 1933 (Folder FF 05-20)
      Poster has a union printing label and features full-face portrait images of the candidates. On back, EB Child. Jan. 1939.
    - "Restore Confidence in your city...McKee...Cuff...Straus...Vote the Key", 1933 (Folder FF 05-20)
      Poster printed by Burland Printing Company, Inc., New York, and has a union printing label. Features full-face portrait images of the candidates.
    - Office of the Mayor (LaGuardia) Posted Notice of March 20, 1935, West Harlem Race Riot (Folder FF 05-20)
      Notice printed by M.B. Brown Printing & Binding Co., N.Y. with union printing label. Notice concerned with spreading false information. Acquisition date(?) in front, Apr. 4, 1935.
    - "Meat is Low -- Taxes are High! Don't Blame Your Butcher", 1936 (Folder FF 05-20)
      Poster has a union printing label. Lists tax (per lb.) of many cuts of meat. On back, "Mrs. Geo. Wilde. Nov. 19, 1936.
    - Sheriff of Monmouth County Proclamation to prevent and punish bribery at Primaries, Conventions, and Elections, 1936 (Folder FF 05-20)
      George H. Roberts was Sheriff. Acquisition date(?) on back, in pencil, Nov. 20, 1936.
    - Republican Candidates on State Ticket, 1936 (Folder FF 05-20)